mCP has really exploded past few weeks
if you want to learn what mCP actually
is there are probably tall videos and
tweets that you can go through already
so I wouldn't dive too deep into that
but today what I really want to talk
about is what kind of startup
opportunity I saw with this mCP
ecosystem blooming and also a stepbystep
process of how can you build a mCP
server from scratch po play and
distribute to others and at extremely
high level mCP basically provides a
unified way for your AI agents or AI
application to access external
assistance as example a few weeks ago I
post this video about how I use all
sorts different mCP in my AI coding
workflow that made AI coding agents a
lot better and if you have been building
AI you probably wondering how is this
mCP different from T call which is
something introduced by open AI almost
two years ago that also allow AI agents
and large L models to take actions
external assistance where the key thing
here is a standard even though large L
model can already take actions in real
world through function calling but each
one of those large L model provider has
different format like open a will
support a two core format looks like
this with name arguments and become part
of conversation history while claw have
a totally different Json format same for
Gemini and llama so each one of those
large L model provider have different
default ways of interacting with
external system but mCP provide a
unified format of how two code should be
communicated if you want to draw some
analogy this somewhat similar to the
early days of Internet there's a portol
called tcpip where before TCP IP each
company has its own standard about how
different device should communicate each
other like IBM have their own protocol
called sna and even Apple has their own
thing called Apple talk they allow
macing touchbased Network to talk to
each other but if you want to build
something that integrate across
different device that means you need to
build custom things for every single
standard but with introduction of
standard like TCP IP everything became
unified which means if you're raer you
just need to build once with this
protocol standard and it allow you to
build for the whole internet and this
changed the value dramatically new
protocol like worldwide web https all
came out and enable business like ncape
yaho Google and internet eventually
became where it is now and this also
part of the reason why I found mCP is so
exciting and we should pay a lot of
attention to it because there will be
lots of opportunities and companies to
be built around this ecosystem for
example with unified protocol like mCP
the entry point for building new AI
agent clients like cursor Wing serve
Manu becomes lower and lower because you
don't need to build all the Integrations
yourself you can just connect to
existing mcps and this kind of draw the
analogy in my mind would be similar to
iPhone windows or even browser like
nascap that directly interact with end
user and those AI agent clients will be
the main driver of adoption for all
sorts different mcps for example this
concept mCP isn't new is introduced
almost 6 months ago but only exploded
recently because with finally have
killer AI agent use case like cursor and
Wing surve which is just one type of use
case like coding agents but with more
vertical AI agents show up like sales
agents customer support agents or even
general purpose agents there will be
needs and requirements for different mCP
servers and on the other hand there also
a lot of opportunity for creating a
Marketplace for mcps there already
existing website like GL and Smith where
they help people to discover what type
of mcps are out there and a lot of hard
work in terms of testing and curating
those mcps it's kind of similar to how
those existing ecosystem has app store
or early days of Yahoo has index page
for people to find the interesting
websites but the most important one is
mCP itself they kind of like apps in app
stores the any iPhone and Android users
can go and access to enhance their
experience and even though at moment mCP
is like a wi web where everything seems
open source and still quite difficult to
use but there are already companies like
20 First Step introduce new products
that is the mCP the existing in clients
like cursor Wing surf that enhance their
coding experience specialized in helping
AI agent to get more context of how to
build beautiful UI and they add G
monetization for those mcps so I
actually expect a lot of new business to
come up that just building mCP and
distribute to All Sorts different users
and to monetize from that that's why
today I want to show you how can you
build a mCP from scratch so that you can
either build mCP for yourself to enhance
your own experience or you can
distribute that to others and even try
out building a mCP based business and
the good thing is that it is not hard
it's actually pretty simple and
straightforward I'll take you through
example of how did I build a figma mCP
from scratch and list down those
Marketplace like glama and symetry but
before I dive into this if you are
launching your own mCP or any type of
product building the product itself just
half the work after the product is built
the next challenge is how to get your
product to the market Market
successfully nine out of 10 business
venture fail and 10% don't even make the
first year and the key difference here
is often how solid your go-to Market
strategy is especially when launching
new prodot type like mCP that's why I
want to introduce you to this free goto
Market playbook for launching new
products then made by hosital they
interview top experts from successful
startups about their best practice
process on PCT launch it covers
step-by-step process of how can you
design a lunch blueprint between Market
product and distribution Channel then
where and how should you go find signals
of the market that your product is
targeting at how to craft the perfect
Market story and step-by-step process to
build your viral tweet it even including
ready to use metric dashboard to track
your new product launch with real world
insights from goto Market experts giving
Hands-On guidance I learned a lot from
this package and I highly recommend you
go and try out if you're planning to
launch a product I put a link in the
description below for you to download
for free now let's get back to how to
build your own mCP so entropic actually
provide specific SDK for python
typescript Java codling so you can use
the language that you are most familiar
with and for me I will be using python
SDK so if you take a look at GitHub here
I'll do pip install mCP so our open
Terminal and just do pip install mCP we
can create a new file called test mCP
dopy so they provide a class called Fast
mCP we can just call this fast mCP class
to initiate a new mCP server with this
one we can just do a decorator mCP do
tool and then Define function here and
when writing the function you can give a
description about what does the function
do as well as what kind of inputs does
it expect and the output to give large L
mod or more context and you can save
this and this mCP is already working we
can quickly go to your mCP settings in
cursor we will right click this file and
copy past and I will just add a new mCP
here I give name my mCP and command will
be mCP run and pasting the pass here and
click add and after it is running you
can see this my mCP has been added
already with the function we defined
here so with this turn on I can already
open the chat and then prompt the cursor
agent help me calculate my bmi where I'm
70 kg with
173 CM height you can see here it call
the calculate BMI function pass on this
two variables and then get result back
so this is how easy it is to actually
set up your mCP server and to practice
this further let's try to build a figma
mCP where can read your figma file and
also convert Your figma Design into hity
react page so first let's take a look at
the figma API so figma actually only
have four end points for you to get data
out one is get file which will return
everything in your specific project file
and get file node allow you to specify a
very specific node ID so in figma every
single UI components you see here on the
left side is a note and you can actually
copy the link to selection and if you
paste the link here you can see that it
also has node ID that point to that
specific frame so this endpoint will
allow to get a very specific component
or page out of figma file as well as get
image and get image will return the
image screenshot of the mup but
unfortunately AI coding agents like
cursor or Wing serve can't really take
image response from mCP yet but with the
first two endpoint we can already do a
lot of cool stuff so I will be using
this endpoint of get file notes to
return the details of specific frame so
I'll create a new EMV and go to my figma
click settings security and click
generate new token given name test and
generate it so you can copy this token
over and paste in here so I go back to
our test mCP file and add a few new
Imports and our load the DMV and load
the figma API token first they create a
helper function called Fetch figma nodes
where it will pass on the file key and
node ID and calling this endpoint which
is what do we see here and then we will
do mCP do2 create function called G Noe
where where we pass on file key and node
ID and our add some descriptions here
that it is to get specific node from
figma file and I will also pass on a bit
of information about what's the file key
and what's node ID and its format and
then our Define function where our Cod
API and point return the response so we
can quickly test out I'm going to copy
the link paste in here and extract file
key and node ID so I'll do python test
mcpi cool and you can see it return uh a
Blog of Json of how does that mup look
like great so this function is working
and all we need to do now just go back
to cursor mCP and if we refresh a little
bit you can see a new function called G
node is showing up here and just to test
this out I can add a new agent and I
will just copy the link and here I have
extremely basic mop so I just right
click copy the link to selection and go
back here and give Implement UI like
figma mop here in Pixel Perfect manner
in index.html you can see it called
again note mcp2 and it return whole
bunch of information about this UI that
we Define in figma then start creating
this HTML page cool so now if we open
this webs page you can see this is Page
generated it kind of get most part right
but some part is looks a bit off and you
might be wondering why and the key
reason here is because if you look at
response in return including whole bunch
of information that is not relevant or
very complicated for large L model to
understand like the color is rgba format
which you can probably communicate in a
lot less token so what we want to do is
we want to clean up the information a
little bit more and this is exactly what
I did so I have a new file called clean
node. py and in here I have a whole
bunch of helper function that can help
you return more clean information and I
actually got a lot of Inspirations from
another mCP server created by Graham but
basically do a whole bunch of clean up
of the information and I can load those
functions from clean node in transform
fig adjacent and come back here at a
clean response equal to this and return
clean response and go to mCP and refresh
again and now let me try this
again and now you can see the UI looks
exactly like the UI we present in figma
file so this how you can build a new mCP
from scratch that's running on locally
but you can also distribute to others
the next thing you want to do is
probably distribute your awesome mCP
server to others and there platforms
like GL or Myster they're providing
existing repository of mcps for you to
distribute to others so all you need to
do just write down a doc with all
dependencies and read me so other people
know how to run this and cursor is
actually pretty good at it so you can
just give a prompt I have this mCP
server implemented help me write the
required. dxt and read me and once it's
done you can upload this project to
GitHub and then go back to like GL click
on ADD server given name description as
well as your GitHub Ripple once you add
that it will go through a process of
reviewing and if everything passed then
other people will be able to search and
install the server directly and I have
already put my figma mCP on glama and
Smith Tre where you can just go and
download and for the figma mCP I will
continue to improve that I already added
new functionalities like get components
so that it can extract all the reusable
components in your figma file as well as
workflow so it can get the figma protype
workflow to better understand the use
flow if you have any feedback or
question about mCP feel free to DM me on
Twitter or you can join my AI Builder
Club Community where I will continue
sharing interesting mCP and AI coding
workflows that I'm experimenting with
detailed breakdown of some my favorite
mCP that I use day-to-day as well as
more in depth course and tutorial about
AI coding and building production agents
but most importantly we have this
community of top AI Builders who might
already experience a problem that you
are facing right now as a solopreneur so
you can come and ask any question you
have to get support I have put the link
to join the community in the description
below I hope you enjoyed this video
please comment about what type of mcps
that you are building or you really want
others to build thank you and I'll see
you next time